<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tor | Forced Far]]></title>
  <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/categories/tor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-28T22:24:24-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://forcedfar.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[forcedfar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Anonymous Internet Identity]]></title>
    <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2013/12/27/an-anonymous-internet-identity/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-27T22:01:56-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2013/12/27/an-anonymous-internet-identity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It turns out that setting up a fully anonymous online identity is more of a hassle than I thought. I expected I would be able to set up a Gmail account through <a href="http://torproject.org">Tor</a>, use that Gmail account to sign up for Twitter and Github, and be self-publishing in no time. Unfortunately, I ran into a few unforeseen problems.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Reputable email providers require phone numbers</h2>

<p>It turns out that Gmail, Yahoo! Mail and whatever Microsoft calls Hotmail these days all require phone verification to set up an account. After a bit of searching, I found that Russia-based Yandex was probably my best option. I don&rsquo;t love that. Because Yandex&rsquo;s mail service is often associated with scammers and spammers, a yandex.com email address is like a nice big red flag to anyone with whom I communicate. If you have a better suggestion for a trustworthy, free webmail provider that will let me sign up through Tor and won&rsquo;t require an email address, please send a message to my Github username at yandex dot com.</p>

<h2>Twitter has suspended my account</h2>

<p>You can try to follow me on <a href="http://twitter.com/forcedfar">Twitter</a>, but I doubt you&rsquo;ll get very far. My account has been suspended. I don&rsquo;t know whether it is due to my creating an account through a Tor node or my yandex email address, but before I had the chance to follow a single soul or tweet a single character, I got a message across the top of my Twitter window:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Your account (@forcedfar) is currently suspended. For more information, please visit <a href="https://twitter.com/account/suspended_help">Suspended Accounts</a>.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>That was fast. Although I <em>did</em> get to skip the page that <del>forces</del> strongly suggests you follow five people before moving on. So I got that going for me. Which is nice. I have submitted a support ticket which I hope will result in access to full use of Twitter. The ticket explained in perfect English how I am not a robot and have no intention of ever being one.</p>

<h2>Some things worked just fine</h2>

<p>The main bright spot was that Github allowed me full use of their platform with no prejudice. I had to do a little Googling to make sure I could push to them through Tor, but Github was accepting of me despite my shady email and dubious IP address. I guess it makes sense that bad actors would be more interested in exploiting services like Twitter over services like Github. There&rsquo;s probably not a lot of money in maliciously contributing to open source projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
