<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Anonymity | Forced Far]]></title>
  <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/categories/anonymity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T00:38:52-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://forcedfar.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[forcedfar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Go Anonymous]]></title>
    <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/why-go-anonymous/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T00:06:48-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/why-go-anonymous</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="/blog/2013/12/31/the-burden-of-anonymity">a previous post</a> I wrote about the difficulty of maintaining my anonymity online. This provokes the question: Why is my anonymity worth the hassle? I have not committed, nor intend to commit any crimes. I do not currently have any stalkers. I am not under investigation by an adversary powerful enough to circumvent the pseudonymity already offered me by my ISP and mainstream internet services. So why am I blogging anonymously?</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Actual freedom of speech</h2>

<p>The Constitution of the United States of America grants to its citizens the right to freedom of speech. This right is rarely exercised to its full extent. Anything we say can and will be held against us and so many of us choose to amend our thoughts or say nothing at all. Behind the mask of Forced Far I can finally speak my mind and I&rsquo;m quite excited to find out what my unfettered mind has to say.</p>

<h2>To see if I can</h2>

<p>Is it even possible today? How hard is it? What are the roadblocks? I already discovered that mainstream email accounts cannot be had anonymously and my Twitter account was suspended <a href="/blog/2014/01/05/twitter-account-unceremoniously-enabled">until just recently</a>. We live in a window in history where it is possible to share our thoughts anonymously and I feel I would be ungrateful if I didn&rsquo;t take advantage of that. I have the added benefit that my blog might serve as something of a guide to someone who needs anonymity more than I do.</p>

<h2>To escape my own perfectionism</h2>

<p>I am an inexperienced writer. I have many ideas that I would blog about, but I stress and worry so much about each one that my output is very, very low. The result of this is that I don&rsquo;t practice writing and I don&rsquo;t get any better. An anonymous blog affords me the opportunity to write freely about my passions without fear of criticism. I can make mistakes and I can change my mind later. Worse comes to worse, I can always throw away Forced Far and begin again with a different pseudonym. I would say that publishing on the internet is like writing something in stone, but stone etchings are susceptible to erosion and will eventually break down. Digital content is forever.</p>

<h2>Protecting myself and others</h2>

<p>I have thoughts and theories that I plan to share that are likely going to piss off powerful groups of people. I have a way of life and people I love and things to lose. I&rsquo;m having trouble finishing this paragraph without being a little ashamed that I&rsquo;m treating myself as some kind of tortured superhero trying to maintain his secret identity. I might not have any super powers. I might end up just a regular nobody in spandex, but I won&rsquo;t really know until I put on the cape.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Account Unceremoniously Enabled]]></title>
    <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2014/01/05/twitter-account-unceremoniously-enabled/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T00:49:34-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2014/01/05/twitter-account-unceremoniously-enabled</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What has two thumbs and can now tweet? <strong>This guy!</strong> <em>Oops!</em> Now you guys totally know how many thumbs I have. sigh. More <a href="/blog/2013/12/31/the-burden-of-anonymity/">leaks</a>.</p>

<p>As mentioned in <a href="/blog/2013/12/28/an-anonymous-internet-identity/">my inaugural post</a>, Twitter judged me not by the content of my character, but by the provider of my free web mail. Or possibly my shady IP address. Either way, measures were taken to preempt my inevitable misbehavior and my stillborn Twitter account was unable to follow or tweet or be followed or anything useful. I opened a support ticket and received no response, but upon checking today I found my Twitter account to be fully functional. I proceeded to follow a few people taking care to give away as little about myself as possible.</p>

<p>This is a positive outcome, for certain. Also, as a bonus, my support ticket remains open. This lends me hope that they may accidentally upgrade my privileges once more and I will be granted use of the coveted one-hundred-and-forty-first character.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Burden of Anonymity]]></title>
    <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2013/12/31/the-burden-of-anonymity/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-31T00:04:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2013/12/31/the-burden-of-anonymity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am one of approximately 7.13 billion people on this planet. Ideally, an adversary would have a one in 7.13 billion chance of connecting Forced Far to my real life identity. However, it is trivial to narrow this down and assume that I am a member of a much smaller subset of the world&rsquo;s population. I am an English-speaking internet user. I know how to use Tor. There are currently approximately three million Tor users. According to some rough estimates and quick back-of-the-envelope math, less than a million Tor users live in English-speaking countries. Even taking every privacy precaution, my blog leaks enough information about me to eliminate over 99.986% of the population. A keen reader will observe that in making those calculations I essentially outed myself as one who lives in an English-speaking country. Leaks upon leaks.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Maintaining my anonymity is already exhausting. Every communication with every account related to Forced Far must take place via Tor. I can&rsquo;t even view my blog without obscuring my IP address because in the early stages I would be the only visitor and therefore likely the originator. When logged in to Twitter, I have to be careful that I don&rsquo;t view tweets or display behaviors that could leak more information. When doing research, I have to do all my searches through Tor. Every website I view and action I take online is potentially stored forever and could be used against me. It&rsquo;s like Benjamin Franklin said: &ldquo;Three men can keep a secret if two of them are dead and none of them received national security letters or used backdoored machines.&rdquo;</p>

<p>This might seem overkill, but the goal is to protect my identity against even the most powerful of adversaries. If my anonymity would be compromised in the event that Github and my ISP are both hacked or forced to give up information under legal duress, then I have no anonymity. This is surprisingly stressful. Although I have taken significant precautions, I can&rsquo;t be sure that I haven&rsquo;t accidentally left a trace. One errant website visit could mean that my unobscured IP address is sitting in a database somewhere waiting like a timebomb to destroy my anonymity in its entirety.</p>

<p>It is also rather difficult to promote this project in an anonymous fashion. My typical first line of promotion for a project like this would be talking it over with friends and family. This way I gain eyeballs and received needed feedback. This time, however, nobody knows that I&rsquo;m even working on a project. It is quite lonely. One day I will write something worth posting to Hacker News or Reddit and people may get curious and a handful may find their way back to this post. For now these words go unnoticed. They are the cry into a crowded room that receives no echo&hellip; or a different, <em>better</em> metaphor that doesn&rsquo;t sound so emo.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Anonymous Internet Identity]]></title>
    <link href="http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/an-anonymous-internet-identity/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-28T22:40:50-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forcedfar.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/an-anonymous-internet-identity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It turns out that setting up a fully anonymous online identity is more of a hassle than I thought. I expected I would be able to set up a Gmail account through <a href="http://torproject.org">Tor</a>, use that Gmail account to sign up for Twitter and Github, and be self-publishing in no time. Unfortunately, I ran into a few unforeseen problems.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Reputable email providers require phone numbers</h2>

<p>It turns out that Gmail, Yahoo! Mail and whatever Microsoft calls Hotmail these days all require phone verification to set up an account. After a bit of searching, I found that Russia-based Yandex was probably my best option. I don&rsquo;t love that. Because Yandex&rsquo;s mail service is often associated with scammers and spammers, a yandex.com email address is like a nice big red flag to anyone with whom I communicate. If you have a better suggestion for a trustworthy, free webmail provider that will let me sign up through Tor and won&rsquo;t require an email address, please send a message to my Github username at yandex dot com.</p>

<h2>Twitter has suspended my account</h2>

<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> <a href="/blog/2014/01/05/twitter-account-unceremoniously-enabled/">Twitter account now enabled</a></p>

<p>You can try to follow me on <a href="http://twitter.com/forcedfar">Twitter</a>, but I doubt you&rsquo;ll get very far. My account has been suspended. I don&rsquo;t know whether it is due to my creating an account through a Tor node or my yandex email address, but before I had the chance to follow a single soul or tweet a single character, I got a message across the top of my Twitter window:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Your account (@forcedfar) is currently suspended. For more information, please visit <a href="https://twitter.com/account/suspended_help">Suspended Accounts</a>.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>That was fast. Although I <em>did</em> get to skip the page that <del>forces</del> strongly suggests you follow five people before moving on. So I got that going for me. Which is nice. I have submitted a support ticket which I hope will result in access to full use of Twitter. The ticket explained in perfect English how I am not a robot and have no intention of ever being one.</p>

<h2>Some things worked just fine</h2>

<p>The main bright spot was that Github allowed me full use of their platform with no prejudice. I had to do a little Googling to make sure I could push to them through Tor, but Github was accepting of me despite my shady email and dubious IP address. I guess it makes sense that bad actors would be more interested in exploiting services like Twitter over services like Github. There&rsquo;s probably not a lot of money in maliciously contributing to open source projects.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
